welcome to another installment of spring
欢迎来到春季的另一期
tips in today's installment we're gonna
今天的分期付款技巧
look at project riff and spring cloud
看项目即兴和春天的云
function project riff is a new project
功能项目riff是一个新项目
from pivotal it's an open source project
从关键到它是一个开源项目
that we started last year and it
我们从去年开始
provides a function as a service runtime
提供功能作为服务运行时
functions as a service have become very
服务即功能已变得非常
very popular of late because they
最近很受欢迎，因为他们
provide an even more concise even more
提供更简洁的内容
abbreviated deployment model for
的简化部署模型
functionality
功能性
remember all as with all things
记住所有事物
economics informs architecture and so we
经济学指导建筑，所以我们
see a lot of people looking to get even
看到很多人希望得到平衡
more agility and they found some
更加敏捷，他们发现了一些
workloads they managed to just describe
他们设法描述的工作量
certain workloads in terms of very
某些工作量非常
simple message in message out style
消息输出样式中的简单消息
semantics and I think this is actually a
语义，我认为这实际上是
really really interesting sort of coming
真的很有趣
of full circle we who have been around
我们周围的人
long enough will probably remember the
足够长的时间可能会记住
term back office right the idea that you
任职后勤办公室的想法，你
had work that didn't belong in the hot
有不属于热门的工作
path of the the front end web
前端网的路径
application the the work that needs to
应用所需的工作
be done that might take a little longer
完成可能需要更长的时间
than for example the milliseconds that
比例如的毫秒数
you can afford for a given request
您可以负担给定的要求
response and typically historically
响应，通常是历史记录
traditionally that work would have been
传统上，这项工作本来是
staged in terms of queues to you so you
就排队给你来说，所以你
would have taken the work put it on a
本来可以把它放在一个
queue and then had something process it
排队，然后进行处理
as appropriate right and this is a you
适当的权利，这是你
know as simple as this idea sounds this
知道这个想法听起来很简单
is the fundamental reason that people
是人们的根本原因
have to start thinking about
必须开始思考
architecture instead of just plowing
建筑而不仅仅是耕作
everything into a giant web application
一切都变成一个巨大的Web应用程序
and for a lot of people this is
对于很多人来说
integration this is messaging this is
集成这是消息这是
the world that that comes out of they
从他们身上出来的世界
need to to be able to do things that
需要能够做一些事情
take a little longer
花一点时间
asynchronous thing so this this whole
异步的东西，所以这整个
world this whole phenomenon of things
世界这整个事物的现象
that I need to do that need to happen
我需要做的事情需要发生
eventually or but not necessarily this
最终或不一定如此
second is still there very much and
第二个仍然在那里
we've certainly got some very nice
我们当然有一些很好的
primitives for solving problems in this
解决这个问题的原语
way obviously in earlier installments of
在早期的分期付款中
spring tips we've looked at a spring
春天的技巧，我们已经看过春天
integration and spring cloud stream and
整合和Spring Cloud Stream和
spring cloud dataflow now going full
春季云数据流现在已满
circle the cloud providers now have a
圈子中的云提供商现在有了一个
approach to modeling discrete units of
离散单元建模的方法
functionality as a single function and
功能作为一个单一的功能和
when they say a function they're not
当他们说一个功能时，他们不是
actually talking necessarily about a
实际上是在谈论一个
language centric concept of a function
以语言为中心的功能概念
but instead this thing that takes a
但是相反，这东西需要
parameter and then returns output so it
参数，然后返回输出，因此它
data in data out very very simple
数据输入非常非常简单
concept and if you extrapolate then this
概念，如果您推断的话
is enough this is a concept that can
够了，这是一个可以
scale out to multiple languages and run
扩展到多种语言并运行
times not just Java or or JavaScript or
时间不只是Java或JavaScript或
or something like that and so you you
或类似的东西，所以你你
you you know that be aware of amazon's
你知道吗，请注意亚马逊的
land
土地
amazon's lambda is a a dubious lambda is
亚马逊的lambda是一个可疑的lambda是
a a runtime for deploying functions in
一个用于在其中部署功能的运行时
certain languages not all languages and
某些语言并非所有语言
the runtime will spin up an instance of
运行时将启动一个实例
your application and for the parameters
您的应用程序和参数
that request pea payloads that are sent
请求豌豆有效载荷被发送
to that function to the function
对那个功能对那个功能
give your function a chance to run and
给您的功能一个运行的机会，
then send a response back out optionally
然后（可选）发送回复
it'll for that that response the output
为此它将响应输出
value to another function and the result
赋予另一个功能和结果
is that you can change things together
是你可以一起改变事物
this was I think the arguably the first
我认为这可以说是第一个
very successful popular function as a
非常成功的流行功能
service runtime but is by no means the
服务运行时，但绝不是
only one at this point all of the big
此时只有一个大
three have options here in the space at
三个在这里的空间
Google and as we're all have very
Google和我们所有人都非常
competitive offerings and there are now
竞争产品，现在有
a number of different open source
许多不同的开源
runtimes as well so obviously there's
运行时也是如此，显然
open wisk
打开拂尘
which is a an open source to run time
这是运行时的开源
and there's um what's that one Oracle
那个甲骨文是什么
just reached one as well Oracle's got
刚刚达到一个甲骨文
one as well so there's a number of
还有一个，所以有很多
different options we have one called
我们有一个不同的选择
project riff riff of course is for
项目riff当然是riff
functions which is to say that riff is
功能就是说即兴
for functions which is to say that riff
对于功能，即即兴
is for form it's a recursive acronym my
是形式，它是递归的首字母缩写
friends it's it has to be a recursive
朋友，那一定是递归的
acronym otherwise it wouldn't be cool so
首字母缩写词，否则它不会很酷
we have a function as a service runtime
我们有一个功能作为服务运行时
and riff is a polyglot function as a
且riff是一个多语言函数
service runtime just like Cloud Foundry
就像Cloud Foundry一样的服务运行时
is a polyglot
是一个多语种
platform as a service and the goal here
平台即服务和目标
is to support the deployment and
是为了支持部署和
lifecycle of functions in discrete units
离散单位中的功能生命周期
of functionality that can be thought of
可以想到的功能
as functions and it's important to have
作为功​​能，拥有
that distinction it's not actually
这种区别实际上不是
necessarily a language level function
一定是语言级别的功能
right we can support for example a batch
好吧，我们可以支持例如一批
script or a shell script right and these
脚本或Shell脚本权利以及这些
shell scripts can take parameters and
Shell脚本可以接受参数和
they can reproduce output so standard in
他们可以复制输出，因此标准
standard out RIF is built on top of
标准输出RIF建立在
kubernetes it's a deployed it's a
kubernetes这是一个部署它是一个
implemented in terms of resources for
在资源方面实施
kubernetes we introduced a couple of new
kubernetes我们引入了一些新的
resources one of which is a topic and
资源之一是一个主题，
another which is a function and you can
另一个是功能，您可以
manage riff on top of any kunas instance
在任何kunas实例上管理riff
obviously we are we have a PKS are kuben
显然我们有一个PKS是kuben
is the pivotal kubernetes service that
是关键的kubernetes服务
that runtime is a I think an ideal fit
我认为运行时非常合适
because it works nicely with cloud
因为它可以很好地与云一起使用
funding but again this will work with
资金，但同样可以
anything so I have riff and kubernetes
任何东西，所以我有即兴和kubernetes
installed in my local machine the docs
在我的本地计算机上安装了文档
here are very thorough there's a number
这是非常彻底的
of different ways to install riff on
安装riff的不同方法
docker for Mac talk of Windows Mini Cube
Mac版Windows Mini Cube的docker
on your local virtual machine which is
在您的本地虚拟机上
what I'm using on my Linux box here and
我在这里的Linux盒子上使用的是什么
of course Google Cloud Google container
当然Google Cloud Google容器
engine well google kubernetes engine
引擎良好的Google kubernetes引擎
that's a on Google all of these are fine
在Google上所有这些都很好
choices and and again anywhere else will
选择，再到其他任何地方
work just fine but the installation is
工作正常，但安装
not that complicated this the gist of it
没有那么复杂的要旨
is that you have to get your cumin is
是你必须得到小茴香
installation up and running somehow so
安装并以某种方式运行
this is fairly easy with mini cube you
使用迷你立方体这很容易
evaluate the the mini cube darker
评估迷你立方体变暗
environment and then finally you use
环境，然后最后您使用
helm helm is a package manager for
helm helm是以下产品的包装经理
kubernetes so use helm we deploy we a
kubernetes，所以使用掌舵我们部署我们
distribute project RIF as a helm chart
将项目RIF分发为头盔图
that you can then use and once you're
然后可以使用，一旦
done with that install Kafka and you
完成安装Kafka之后，您
wait for things to spin up and there you
等待事物旋转起来，在那里
are
是
you have a fully working runtime the
您有一个可以正常运行的运行时
only thing you'll need then is a CLI so
那么您唯一需要的就是CLI，因此
you can download that CLI and then you
您可以下载该CLI，然后
install invoker's and these invoker's
安装调用者和这些调用者的
are the things that actually invoke your
是真正调用您的东西的东西
functions right these are sort of
正确的功能是
sidecars that run in the container that
在集装箱中运行的小车
take messages coming off of queues in
从队列中取出消息
this case Kafka
这种情况下卡夫卡
and then for them to your functions now
然后为他们执行您的功能
if your function isn't running right if
如果您的功能运行不正确，如果
you haven't run it yet then this sidecar
您还没有运行它，那么这辆挎斗车
will make sure that there's an instance
确保有一个实例
available to handle it and if there is
可以处理它，如果有的话
no more traffic if you send one request
如果您发送一个请求，则不再有流量
and then wait fifteen seconds which is
然后等待十五秒
the default timeout then you will get a
默认超时，那么您将获得一个
you will see that the function will
您会看到该功能将
scale down to zero you'll have zero
缩小到零，您将得到零
instances of the function running if
运行该函数的实例，如果
however there is successive requests
但是有连续的请求
there are successive requests that
有连续的请求
happen in that 15-second interval then
发生在15秒间隔内
the same image will be reused to serve
同一张图片将被重新使用
those multiple successive invocations
那些连续的多次调用
and if you have an overwhelming deluge
如果您有大量的洪水
of traffic that can't be effectively
无法有效处理的流量
handled that is to say your availability
处理就是说你有空
goes down then the the runtime will
下来然后运行时将
scale it up as needed it'll scale up to
根据需要扩大规模，将扩大规模
two instances five 100 whatever it's
两个实例5个100
whatever is required to be able to
需要什么才能
satisfy the demand and then eventually
满足需求，然后最终
as I say it'll scale back down to zero
正如我说的那样，它将缩小为零
instances this is what vendors mean when
实例，这就是供应商在什么时候的意思
they say that function has a certain
他们说功能有一定
times or service run times scale to zero
时间或服务运行时间缩放为零
the consequence of course of scaling to
当然扩展到
zero is that you are going to have to
零是你将不得不
pay the cold start tax right so the next
正确支付冷启动税，所以接下来
time there's a request it's going to
有要求的时候
boot up that image that has your
启动具有您的图像
function including the sidecar and and
功能包括边车和
then wait for it to spin up right well
然后等它旋转好
this means that if you're running a
这意味着如果您正在运行
Python function or a Java function or or
Python函数或Java函数或
or whatever
管他呢
then you have to wait for that runtime
那么你必须等待那个运行时
to start up right and that's what I
正确开始，这就是我的目的
that's why I think these are ideally
这就是为什么我认为这些都是理想的
suited sort of for back office things
适合后勤工作
for which a second startup tax is not so
第二个启动税不是这样
problematic especially since we know
有问题的，尤其是因为我们知道
that result will come it's just not
结果会到来，只是没有
gonna necessarily come immediately it'll
一定会马上来
be staged through through queues you're
被排在队列中
not gonna lose data big also because you
不会因为你而丢失大量数据
have those queues so let's go ahead and
有那些队列，让我们继续前进，
take a look at this let's go ahead and
看看这个，让我们继续
look at some simple examples here now
现在看一些简单的例子
keep in mind this is a Multi multi
请记住，这是一个多多
language runtime multi-platform runtime
语言运行时多平台运行时
is as you can see from these different
从这些不同中可以看到
invoker's here that there's a support
调用者在这里有支持
for command these are shell scripts you
对于命令，这些是shell脚本
know bin sh shell scripts there's go you
知道bin sh shell脚本就可以了
know they'll go language Java which is
知道他们会用Java语言
the one
唯一的那个
we're gonna spend most of our time with
我们将大部分时间都花在
here today node as a nodejs and then of
今天的节点是一个nodejs，然后是
course Python 3 so all these are our
当然是Python 3，所以这些都是我们的
support of the box and it wouldn't be
盒子的支持，它不会
hard to to add support for more the the
很难添加更多的支持
runtime itself it's written in go right
运行时本身写在正确的位置
so we have a lot of different options
所以我们有很多不同的选择
here a lot of different supported
这里有很多不同的支持
technologies ok so let's go ahead and
技术还不错，让我们继续前进，
get started we're gonna go ahead and
开始，我们将继续前进，
just get started with a very simple
刚开始非常简单
example I have in the background here
我在后台的例子
Coop's detail it's on a watch it's a
Coop的细节在手表上
every 1 second refreshing
每1秒刷新一次
Coop's detail or coupe cuddle get pods
Coop的细节或双门轿跑车拥抱
deployments in getting all the
部署以获取所有
namespaces right so there's that I'm
正确的名称空间，所以我
gonna actually run something different
实际上会有所不同
here I'll run demo which will show me a
在这里，我将运行演示，它将向我展示
lot more for me the functions the topics
对我来说，功能更多
the deployments and the pause alright so
部署和暂停都可以
you can see I've got nothing there I've
你可以看到我什么都没有
also got RIF the CLI so let's do eval
也有了RIF CLI，让我们评估一下
mini cube docker env first just to make
迷你立方体docker env首先要做
sure that our docker context is pointing
确保我们的Docker上下文指向
to the right time and time there and
到正确的时间和地点
I'll say riff list when I do that I see
我会说重复列表
there's nothing there okay now I've got
现在什么都没有了
nothing in my directory here either so
我的目录中什么也没有
I'm gonna go ahead and let's go ahead
我要去吧，我们去吧
and build a very very simple example
并建立一个非常非常简单的例子
we'll start with a ain't no digest
我们将从根本上开始
example which is a little sacrosanct I
我有点神圣的例子
know but we're gonna do it because I
知道，但我们要去做，因为我
want to I want to have a lot of
想要我想要很多
different options here so we're gonna
这里有不同的选择，所以我们要
sue when I create the the example that's
在创建示例时提起诉讼
you know a very very very
你知道一个非常非常非常
straightforward example that'll reverse
简单的例子将扭转
a string okay so reverse and we're gonna
一串好吧，所以反向，我们要
create a reverse j/s file and it'll just
创建一个反向j / s文件，它只会
be a node module so module dot exports
成为节点模块，以便模块点导出
equals string lambda syntax I was get
等于我得到的字符串lambda语法
that confused it because it's a
搞混了，因为它是一个
different from Kaufmann and Java but
与Kaufmann和Java不同，但
it's similar to Scala and then we're
它类似于Scala，然后我们
gonna take the string that comes in and
要拿进来的弦
split it what we're doing is were
拆分它，我们正在做的是
creating a lambda here right so the
在这里创建一个lambda，所以
input is the string that's going to be
输入是将要使用的字符串
sent from the client and the client by
从客户端和客户端发送的
the way is gonna post to the function as
方式将发布到函数
a servicing gateway the HTTP gateway
服务网关HTTP网关
that is how messages arrive into the
这就是消息到达的方式
system so you don't get control over the
系统，这样您就无法控制
URLs you don't get control over you know
您无法控制的URL
the the address ability of any
任何人的地址能力
particular function it just is what it
特定功能就是它
is and again this is
是又是这个
the reason why I would use this for back
我为什么要用这个来回
in kind of stuff back office kind of
在后台的东西
work so I'm gonna take the string and
工作，所以我要把弦和
split it by empty quote I would say it's
用空引号将其拆分，我会说这是
gonna turn into an array it'll take each
会变成一个数组，每个数组都需要
character
字符
it'll take each character and turn that
它会把每个角色都变成
into an element in a different array and
放入另一个数组中的元素中，
in an array then I'm gonna reverse the
在一个数组中，然后我将反转
array then I'm gonna join the whole
数组，然后我将加入整个
thing back together
一起回来
like so again fairly trivial example but
像这样再小例子
it does demonstrate what we're trying to
它确实证明了我们正在努力
do and now we have this file here in a
做，现在我们在这里有这个文件
directory called reverse so I want to
目录称为反向，所以我想
say riff create node so I'm gonna create
说riff创建节点，所以我要创建
a node function and again keep in mind
节点功能，并再次牢记
we're going to create a function named
我们将创建一个名为
reverse and we want this function to be
反向，我们希望这个功能是
addressable on the input kafka topic
可在输入kafka主题上解决
called reverse so whenever somebody
叫反向，所以每当有人
sends a payload into the reverse topic
将有效载荷发送到反向主题
it'll end up in our function so I'm
它会结束我们的功能，所以我
gonna call that input topic reverse now
现在将那个输入主题叫作反向
we could specify an output topic right
我们可以指定一个输出主题
we'll see that in a minute but for our
我们会在一分钟内看到，但对于我们
purposes it's Spice's believe this as is
目的是Spice相信的是
so gonna say create node named reverse
所以要说创建名为reverse的节点
input reverse and file path will be
输入反向，文件路径为
equal to this okay so that's gonna
等于这个好吧，那会
create a number of different artifacts
创建许多不同的工件
here you can see we have a the docker
在这里您可以看到我们有一个码头工人
file that describes our function and we
描述我们功能的文件
can see that the docker file really it's
可以看到docker文件确实是
just a simple doctor father extends from
只是一个简单的医生父亲从
the node function invoker adding our
节点函数调用者添加了
little script and providing the function
小脚本并提供功能
URL okay and the node function of okra
URL正常和okra的节点功能
will know to look at this function and
会知道看看这个功能，
to invoke it and then take the output of
调用它，然后输出
that and put it on the output Kafka
并将其放在输出卡夫卡上
queue or send it back to the as a
排队或将其作为
response if you like all right so that's
如果您喜欢的话，请回复
this and then you can see there's also
这个然后你可以看到那里
kubernetes llamo files config files for
kubernetes llamo文件的配置文件
they do different resources here so
他们在这里做不同的资源
particularly you've got reverse topics
特别是你有反向主题
gamal all right that's just the Kefka
没错，就是凯夫卡
topic nothing I don't usually I don't
没事我通常不会
usually have to to mess with that but
通常不得不搞混，但是
it's there if you want it and reverse
如果你想要它就在那里，然后反向
function llamo this is a little bit more
功能llamo这要多一点
interesting so you can see here that
有趣，所以你可以在这里看到
it's a you know fairly straightforward
这是你知道的很简单
we're gonna see later on that it's
我们稍后会看到
useful sometimes to be able to fill with
有时很有用
this container segment here this stanza
此节中的此容器段
here but basically we're saying this is
在这里，但基本上我们是说这是
a function
一个功能
the the inputs are going to be coming in
输入将要输入
on the the G RPC protocol you know so
您知道的G RPC协议上
the function invoker speaks trpc2 the to
函数调用程序将trpc2讲给
the function and you know it gets turned
该功能，您知道它被打开了
into the payload that we then recognize
进入我们可以识别的有效载荷
and you can work with and that's it
您可以与之合作，就是这样
right that's the sum total of all that
对，那是所有东西的总和
let's see the whole thing and now if you
让我们看看整个事情，现在，如果你
riff list you can see we've got a
即兴演奏列表，您可以看到我们有一个
function in there so let's go ahead and
功能在那里，所以让我们继续
try publishing a result or a request
尝试发布结果或请求
rather to it I could continue spelling
宁可继续拼写
out input but in all these different
输入，但所有这些不同
commands you can use I and n so I is
您可以使用I和n的命令，所以我是
input and his name here I only need
输入和他的名字在这里我只需要
since I'm sending a request I only need
因为我正在发送请求，所以我只需要
to specify the input Kafka on which the
指定输入卡夫卡
Kafka topic on which I want the request
我想要请求的Kafka主题
to arrive so I will say riff publish and
到达所以我会说即兴发布和
then we called this they called this
然后我们叫这个他们叫这个
reverse right it's it's up there in the
反向对，它就在那里
name there so reverse and then we will
在此命名，然后反向，然后我们将
specify some payload some data so we'll
指定一些有效载荷一些数据，所以我们将
say hello world alright and then we're
打个招呼世界，然后我们
gonna say that we want the response to
要说我们要回应
come back if we don't specify response
如果我们不指定回应，请回来
minus R or you know expecting a reply if
减R或您知道期待答复，如果
we don't specify it'll be a
我们没有指定它将是
fire-and-forget so it'll be sent over
一劳永逸，将其发送过来
the coffee cup queue and it'll be
咖啡杯队列，它将
delivered when possible ASAP right but I
在可能的情况下尽快交付但我
want the response I want to see the
想要我想看到的回应
results so I'll wait for that response
结果，所以我将等待该响应
to spin up alright so there we are
好吧，所以我们
there's our very simple hello world
这是我们非常简单的世界
example using no digest now again a
再次不使用摘要的示例
little slow obviously very it's a little
有点慢，很明显，有点
slow and the first time first time you
慢，第一次是第一次
send a request but if we do it enough
发送请求，但如果我们做得足够
times you can see that it's a fairly
时代，你会看到这是一个相当
quick write the result this goes to a
快速写结果，这将
Kafka queue hits the function gets put
Kafka队列命中功能被放置
back on a Kafka queue and get sent back
回到Kafka队列并发送回去
and we get it done you know it gets sent
我们做到了，您知道它已经发送了
to or through the heb gateway and back
到或通过heb网关再返回
you know as HTTP all in that split
你知道作为HTTP所有
second again if we wait a few seconds
再等几秒钟
though if we wait 15 seconds to e to be
但是如果我们等15秒钟才能成为
precise then we make the request you can
精确，那么我们可以提出您的要求
see that we have to wait for it to spin
看到我们必须等待它旋转
up here and you can see that it's doing
在这里，你可以看到它正在做
that here right you can see it it's spun
在这里，您可以看到它旋转了
up you know as we as we wanted it to
你知道我们想要的那样
okay now we've got the reverse function
好吧，现在我们有了反向功能
that's a node let's go ahead and create
这是一个节点，让我们继续进行创建
a Java version obviously so here we can
Java版本，因此在这里我们可以
spring cloud function now spring cloud
春天云功能现在春天云
function is a new project from the
函数是来自的新项目
spring cloud team there are
Spring Cloud团队有
unfortunately not just yet checkboxes
不幸的是，还没有复选框
here on the initializer but I have a
在初始化器上，但是我有一个
suspicion that'll be there in a month or
怀疑一个月后会在那里
so so all we need I think for our
所以我们需要的是我的想法
purposes of Lombok maybe you could use
龙目岛的目的也许你可以使用
any language again anything on the JVM
再次使用任何语言在JVM上进行任何操作
will work just fine anything at
在任何地方都可以正常工作
Springwood who can work with including
可以与之合作的Springwood包括
Scala for example would work just fine
例如Scala就可以了
but we're going to just leave it in Java
但是我们将其保留在Java中
because it's a simple simple enough
因为这很简单
example so we'll hit generate and what
例子，所以我们将点击generate以及
we're gonna do is we're gonna kind of
我们要做的是
function that takes that reverse string
接受反向字符串的函数
and uppercases it we're going to
和大写字母，我们要
uppercase the string and then send it to
将字符串大写，然后将其发送到
the other world or to the reverse
另一个世界或相反
function so now I've got uppercase and
功能，所以现在我已经大写了，
I'm going to add spring cloud function
我要添加Spring Cloud功能
now it's spring cloud function is a as I
现在它的春天云功能就像我
say it's a new project its purpose is to
说这是一个新项目，其目的是
allow you to write functions and then
允许您编写函数，然后
adapt them to different function as a
使它们适应不同的功能
service runtimes of which project riff
项目riff的服务运行时
is just one so this is a it's a nice
只是一个所以这是一个很好
technology to have that I have an
技术让我拥有
example I'm a github I can link to it
我是一个github我可以链接到它
and a readme for the example for this on
和有关此示例的自述文件
spring - tips on github you'll see the
春季-有关github的技巧，您将看到
the code for this I have an example that
为此的代码我有一个例子
use the spring Club function for example
例如使用spring俱乐部功能
to deploy you know the Gateway the the
部署您知道网关
endpoint and the function itself and all
端点，函数本身以及所有
this other stuff that you need for ATM
ATM需要的其他东西
is lambda so it's a it's tedious to use
是lambda，所以使用起来很繁琐
native sign up because lambda requires
本机注册，因为lambda需要
you have all these extra types on the
您在所有这些额外的类型
craft path in order for it to work and
工艺路径，以便它起作用
the goal of a sprinkler function is to
洒水功能的目标是
adapt you adapt your function as much as
尽可能地适应您的功能
possible from the underlying or runtime
可能来自基础或运行时
or agent to extricated from the
或代理商从中解脱
underlying runtime while allowing it to
基础运行时，同时允许
remain portable so again with the use of
保持便携性，因此再次使用
adapters and the right maven
适配器和合适的专家
configuration you can take this code
配置可以使用此代码
that we're going to write here right now
我们现在要在这里写
and eventually with you know a lot more
最终与您一起了解更多
configuration get it to work on a team
配置使其可以在团队中工作
spend and that's not consideration
花钱，这不是考虑
required because of spring is just
因为春天是必需的
configuration because of a davis lambda
由于davis lambda而配置
which is actually pretty tedious the ATM
这实际上是非常乏味的ATM
is lambda has a an easy-to-use sort of 5
是lambda的一种易于使用的5
minute demo use case which is you'll log
分钟演示用例，您将在其中记录
in you upload a jar hit deploy click a
在您上传jar时，点击部署单击
checkbox or two or 10 and you get a
复选框或两个或十个，您会得到一个
gateway and you can make a request to
网关，您可以请求
the Gateway but
门户但是
want to automate that then it gets
想要自动化，然后得到
particularly burdensome so I'm not gonna
特别沉重，所以我不会
waste the next hour trying to get all
浪费下一个小时试图全力以赴
that done here for us you know because I
在这里为我们所做的，你知道，因为我
don't really I don't care and then also
真的不是我不在乎，然后
we have party trip which is much simpler
我们有派对旅行，这很简单
so all we're gonna do is going to add
所以我们要做的就是添加
spring cloud function and it'll do the
春天的云功能，它会做
rest
休息
so spring cloud function dependencies I
所以春天云功能依赖我
have this in my local class path if you
如果您在我的本地课程路径中有这个
don't have in your local class path
不在您当地的课程路径中
you'll add you'll need to add the maven
您将添加您需要添加行家
snapshot repository for spring so it's
春天的快照存储库，所以
spring that IO
春天那个IO
you know it's out there so yeah if you
你知道那儿在那里，是的，如果你
go to start the spring that IO and
去开始IO和
choose snapshot for something Adam
为亚当选择快照
automatically add it for you but I don't
自动为您添加它，但我没有
need to I forgot to do that it doesn't
我需要忘记这样做
matter still work type is equal to palm
物质仍然起作用类型等于手掌
okay so there we are there's the
好吧，所以我们在那里
dependencies that I need you would need
我需要的依赖项
a dependency you don't need a repository
您不需要存储库的依赖项
stanza if you'd if you've never done
如果您从未用过，请添加节
this and then finally I'm just gonna go
这个，最后我要走了
ahead and add spring cloud function
提前添加弹簧云功能
starter web all right that's the web
入门网站好吧就是网站
dependency that's the web support for it
Web对其的依赖
spring tide function all right now that
现在的春季潮汐功能
that's on the class path let's go ahead
在课堂上，让我们继续前进
and build a very simple function here
在这里建立一个非常简单的功能
and the whole point of this is to to
整个重点是
create a very simple function that can
创建一个非常简单的功能
uppercase a string so you say function
大写一个字符串，所以你说函数
literally just function W till 8 other
字面上只是函数W直到其他8个
this is Java 8 or better function and we
这是Java 8或更好的功能，我们
could do this a couple ways we could say
可以通过几种方式做到这一点
I want to take a string and then return
我想取一个字符串然后返回
a string like so so you say return input
像这样的字符串，所以你说返回输入
input becomes to uppercase that's output
输入变成输出的大写
all right that's certainly one option
好吧那当然是一种选择
couldn't get simpler or and I think this
无法简单化，或者我认为
is more useful well in a lot of cases we
在很多情况下更有用
could use the reactive streams
可以使用反应流
publisher you know type and particular
您知道类型和特定的发布者
we can use the react reactor project
我们可以使用反应堆项目
which is the reactive runtime that build
这是构建的反应式运行时
on top of reactive streams we can use
除了反应流之外，我们可以使用
the reactor reactor project to to
反应堆反应堆项目
describe the incoming stream of requests
描述传入的请求流
as a flux a flux is a publisher to think
作为通量，通量是出版商要思考的
that emits items just
只是散发物品
reacted streams publisher implements the
反应的流发布者实现了
reactive streams publisher interface but
反应性流发布者界面，但是
it is a thing that omits items and it
这是一个省略项目的东西，它
could be potentially unbounded so it has
可能是无限的，所以它有
operators that we can use to to iterate
我们可以用来迭代的运算符
traverse filter or whatever over the the
遍历过滤器或
values just like a like we would want to
就像我们想要的那样
do so here I'm gonna say function flux
在这里我要说函数通量
of string it's going to produce a flux
会产生助焊剂
of string all right so uppercase return
字符串正确，所以大写返回
no let's get this compiling flux did I
不，让我们得到这个编译通量
miss it append see here spring cloud
错过它附录在这里看到春天的云
function
功能
starter function web yeah here we go all
入门功能网站，是的，我们全力以赴
right so that in this case is a incoming
对，这样在这种情况下
flux I'm gonna say incoming flux dot map
我要说来的助焊剂点图
you know s that's the string dot to
你知道那是字符串点
uppercase so again this is a reactive
大写，所以这又是一个反应
API right I can I can use the reactive
API对，我可以使用反应式
web client from Spring Framework five
Spring Framework的Web客户端五
this is all stuff that was introduced in
这是所有引入的东西
I don't have the director will climb but
我没有导演会爬，但是
if I added the reactive web client type
如果我添加了反应式Web客户端类型
I could use that to call other services
我可以用它来呼叫其他服务
I could do all sorts of interesting
我可以做各种有趣的事
things here and those be non-blocking
这里的东西和那些不阻塞的东西
right and that's very valuable here so
对，这在这里非常有价值
in this case it's fine let's go ahead
在这种情况下，我们继续吧
and just leave it as is when the request
并在请求时保持原样
comes in we're gonna take the incoming
进来，我们要拿来
request uppercase it and then send it
请求大写然后发送
out as a reactive stream outward that's
作为反应流向外流出
gonna be all you know inputs or and
将成为您所知道的输入或
outputs are still gonna be managed by
输出仍将由
kafka but now we can have this nice
卡夫卡，但现在我们可以有这个好
program model which integrates with
程序模型与
other things that want to you know that
其他想要你知道的事情
we want to talk to in terms of these
我们想谈谈这些
reactive types all right so uppercase
反应性类型可以，所以大写
maven clean package
Maven清洁包
all right and I'm gonna say I'm gonna
好吧，我要说我要
say riff create create Java I is input
说riff创建创建Java我输入
remember so uppercase name again - and
再次记住大写的名字-和
his name shortcut for that is uppercase
他的名字快捷方式是大写
because why not
因为为什么不
Oh is the is the reverse is the Kafka
哦是相反的是卡夫卡
topic eight that want to for the
想要的主题八
response to and in this case we're gonna
回应，在这种情况下，我们将
forward it on to our reverse so it'll
将其转发给我们的反向，这样它会
it'll have the effect of chaining these
会产生连锁效果
two different things written in
用两种不同的东西写
different languages and by the way this
不同的语言，顺便说一下
is one of the one of the really
是真正的之一
interesting possibilities as with paths
路径的有趣可能性
as with faz you get the ability to to
与faz一样，您有能力
mix and match the best of breed
混合搭配最佳品种
technologies for the job at hand
用于手头工作的技术
obviously these are fairly lightweight
这些显然很轻巧
trivial examples but maybe you want to
琐碎的例子，但也许你想
use something that's written in shell
使用用Shell写的东西
right or invoke something that's written
对或调用已写的内容
alright more readily accessible inside
好在里面更容易访问
of a shell script well I think some of
一个shell脚本，我认为
the ugliest code I've ever seen it has
我见过的最丑陋的代码
to do with the integration of Java and
与Java和
native code as you might for example
例如，您可能会使用本机代码
with J&amp;I or Java and operating system
与J＆I或Java和操作系统一起使用
command line utilities you know a shell
您知道外壳的命令行实用程序
scripting shelling out to a command on
脚本化到命令
the operating system that kind of code
操作系统那种代码
is tedious it's hard to guarantee that
乏味，很难保证
it works you know it's just something I
它可以工作，你知道那只是我的事
like to keep isolated and if you've ever
喜欢保持孤立，如果你曾经
used for example the imagemagick
例如用于imagemagick
Java binding you know that some of this
Java绑定你知道其中一些
stuff sometimes leaks right so it's just
东西有时会泄漏正确，所以
really nice to have this opportunity
很高兴有这个机会
this option to say okay this is for
这个选项说好，这是为了
example a command it is off by itself
例如一个命令，它本身是关闭的
I'm gonna start it up do some processing
我要开始做一些处理
and then kill the container and claim
然后杀死容器并声称
all that memory there's no possibility
所有的记忆是不可能的
of a leak in my java application right
我的Java应用程序泄漏的原因
in this case I can in this case it's
在这种情况下，我可以在这种情况下
just a node to just example so really
只是一个例子而已
nothing games but imagine for example
没什么游戏，但想像一下
that imagemagick scenario imagine you
imagemagick场景想像你
wanted to have something that that did
想要做某件事
some did something with Java in Java and
有些人在Java中用Java做过一些事情，
then forward the response off to image
然后将响应转发到图像
managed to do some actual image resizing
设法做一些实际的图像调整大小
well use you can use the API itself you
好好使用，您可以使用API​​本身
can use the ffmpeg you use all these
可以使用ffmpeg使用所有这些
command line utilities that are much
命令行实用程序很多
more readily you know manipulated on the
您更容易知道在
command line and then they are through
命令行，然后他们通过
some third-party
一些第三方
j9 binding for example okay so riff
J9绑定例如好吧，即兴
create Java - I uppercase
创建Java-我大写
and is it uppercase out is reversed
它是大写出来是反向的
we're forwarding it on to our node is it
我们将其转发到我们的节点上
that is a handler the artifact that we
这是一个处理程序，我们
want to use to run this is upper case
想用来运行这是大写
snapshot jar so before I use - - file
快照jar，所以在使用前--文件
path and I said just figure it out by
路径，我说只是想办法
looking at the current directory here
在这里查看当前目录
I'm being very specific there's a lot of
我很具体，有很多
things in the current directory just
当前目录中的内容
because of the nature of the multi
由于多重性
directory file system and structure for
目录文件系统和结构
a java application and then finally I'm
一个Java应用程序，然后我终于
gonna tell it what to run so I'm gonna
要告诉它要运行什么，所以我要
say I want you to run this function
说我要你运行这个功能
called uppercase inside of this class
在此类中称为大写
I'm going to give it to two bits of
我将把它分成两部分
information here uppercase that's the
这里的信息是大写的
function itself and the main class is
功能本身，主要类别是
this right now it is my hope that the
现在，我希望
Java function invoker gets to the point
Java函数调用器达到目的
where I can say okay you know I don't
我可以说好吧，你知道我不知道
need to specify the handler here's the
需要在这里指定处理程序
jar it's a spring good app just figure
罐子，这是一个很好的春季应用程序
out the bean that has that it then
取出有它的豆子
implements function or better yet just
实现功能或更佳
here you know here's the name of the
在这里，你知道这是
function to look for but for now this is
要查找的功能，但现在这是
not a big deal all right you can see our
没什么大不了的，你可以看到我们的
function and our uppercase R have them
函数和我们的大写R拥有它们
both - been deployed and you know our
两者-已部署，您知道我们的
reverse Center uppercase R but both been
反转中心大写字母R，但都
deployed and we can interrogate the
部署，我们可以询问
runtime and ask it what functions we've
运行时，问一下我们有什么功能
got available to us now so those are
现在可供我们使用，所以这些是
both there and what I want to do is I
在那里，我想做的是
want to send a request to the uppercase
想要发送请求到大写
hello beautiful riff and that's the - T
你好美丽的即兴即兴-T
is the data right just like an the curl
像卷发一样是正确的数据吗
command and by the way if you were doing
命令，顺便说一句，如果你在做
something more complicated you wanted to
你想做的更复杂的事情
UM to for example send JSON stanzas you
UM例如向您发送JSON节
could do that you could actually say
可以做到，你实际上可以说
application you know content type equals
您知道内容类型等于的应用程序
application JSON and then this case the
应用程序JSON，然后是这种情况
flux of string could be a flux of you
字符串的变化可能是你的变化
know whatever it could be input private
知道什么可以私人输入
string value and then you could have a
字符串值，然后您可能会有一个
flux of inputs and then make sure you
输入流量，然后确保您
have getters and setters its axon
有吸气剂和二传手的轴突
marshalling of course but you know that
编组当然，但你知道
would work as well as long as you
只要你能正常工作
specify the content type it'll do
指定它将执行的内容类型
marshalling with the strings so by
用绳子编组，所以
default the runtime itself knows about
默认情况下，运行时本身知道
strings they get moved in
他们被移进去的弦
but there's no reason you couldn't turn
但是没有理由你不能转身
these things into more interesting types
这些东西变成更有趣的类型
based on your languages support for
根据您的语言支持
marshaling and so on okay so we're gonna
编组等等，好吧，我们要
say publish this to the uppercase kafka
说将其发布到大写的卡夫卡
topic sending this message we don't need
发送此消息的主题，我们不需要
to specify the content type it's just
指定内容类型
implied and that's it and we want to
暗示就是这样，我们想要
specify a runt reply now remember I've
指定一个矮小的答复现在记得我已经
chained this to talk to Reverse so we
将其链接以与Reverse交谈，因此我们
should see it take our lowercase hello
应该看到它占用了我们的小写字母你好
beautiful riff uppercase it and reverse
美丽的即兴大写字母它和反向
it okay container creating running
好的，容器正在创建运行
there's the reverse it's now running as
相反，它现在以
well and there we go
好吧，我们去
hello bootiful riff alright so that work
你好，战利品即兴好，这样工作
that's a very simple example of two
这是两个非常简单的例子
functions chained together in this way
通过这种方式将功能链接在一起
and you can do all sorts of interesting
你可以做各种有趣的事
things here I mean you know I gave you
这里的事情我的意思是你知道我给了你
some examples but let's talk about a
一些例子，但让我们谈谈
more typical scenario something that is
更典型的情况是
sort of long-running I I like I
像我这样长期运行的II
mentioned the image magic thing because
提到图像魔术的东西，因为
I'm sure we've all had code in our
我确定我们所有人中都有代码
system somewhere that has to shell out
系统必须要炮轰的地方
that's a common enough thing but even in
这是很普通的事情，但即使在
Java we have things that are we would
Java我们拥有的东西
prefer to have done outside of the
宁愿在外面做
traditional request response path of our
我们的传统请求响应路径
application and for some things for
应用程序和一些东西
which we can be sure it will eventually
我们可以肯定它最终会
succeed we can use for example at at
成功，我们可以使用例如
async and absolutely one option but that
异步，绝对是一种选择，但是那
assumes that the runtime will always be
假设运行时总是
there that the application will never
那里的应用程序永远不会
lose any state so I'm I tend to shy away
失去任何状态，所以我倾向于回避
from that useful though that is I try
从那有用的虽然我尝试
and keep things staged through queues
并通过排队让事情上演
right the staged event-driven
对上演的事件驱动
architecture very very simple so and the
建筑非常非常简单，所以
reason I do that is because if I should
我这样做的原因是因为如果我应该
lose you know if my client the thing
让你知道我的客户是否有事
that's creating the work should ever
创造作品应该永远
should it should fail then I can at
如果它应该失败，那么我可以在
least restart the client and a little
最少重启客户端一点
reprocess he missed it missed messages
重新处理他错过了错过的消息
and we have that built in now this is
现在我们已经内置了
this comes for free that guarantee of of
这是免费的，保证的
the staged event-driven architecture
分阶段的事件驱动架构
approach that's already here it's just
已经存在的方法
there for free out of the box so let's
可以免费使用，所以让我们
go ahead and build a Springwood
来建造斯普林伍德
application that sends email and what
发送电子邮件的应用程序以及什么
we're gonna do is we're gonna send email
我们要做的是发送电子邮件
using send grid now send good is a email
现在使用发送网格发送好是一封电子邮件
as a service sort of
作为一种服务
runtime it's a it's a sad offering that
运行时，这是一个令人遗憾的选择
has an API and it needs an API key so
有一个API，它需要一个API密钥，因此
this will what we're gonna do is were
这将是我们要做的是
going to use the SendGrid api to just to
将使用SendGrid API只是为了
authenticate and we'll use the client
进行身份验证，我们将使用客户端
java binding to create the right payload
Java绑定以创建正确的有效负载
to then send that request and so on in
然后发送该请求，依此类推
order for this to work though we need an
为了使它工作，尽管我们需要一个
environment variable okay so we need to
环境变量好吧，所以我们需要
we need some somewhere to stash the
我们需要一些地方藏起来
authentication api key so let's go ahead
身份验证api密钥，让我们继续
and close this and create a new function
并关闭它并创建一个新功能
and this one will be called mailer all
这将被称为mailer all
right Manor
右庄园
so um I don't know that we need all that
所以，我不知道我们需要所有这些
much from this I guess we could use
我想我们可以从中使用很多
Lombok but actually we don't even need
龙目岛，但实际上我们甚至不需要
that really so this is just a very
真的，所以这只是一个非常
simple Springwood app I'll hit generate
我将点击生成的简单Springwood应用程序
and that'll give us this Maynard unzip
这会给我们这个Maynard解压缩
that we're gonna open up in our
我们将会在我们的
application and our IDE and
应用程序和我们的IDE
now before we can you know what we need
现在我们才能知道我们需要什么
to do is we need to add the normal stuff
要做的是我们需要添加普通的东西
that we just did before the dependency
我们在依赖之前所做的
is first of all not already dependencies
首先不是已经依赖
dependency and sprinkler function
依赖和洒水功能
dependencies type is equal to palm scope
依赖项类型等于Palm作用域
import all right so there's that and we
导入好吧，就是这样，我们
need the spring code function starter
需要弹簧代码功能启动器
function web everyone okay so there's
功能网络每个人都很好，所以有
our dependencies now we also need the
我们的依赖关系现在我们还需要
SendGrid api we need the same grid
SendGrid API，我们需要相同的网格
client on the class path here so let's
客户在这里的课堂路径上，所以让我们
go ahead and add a dependency for that
继续并为此添加依赖项
okay the SendGrid dependency lives at
好的，SendGrid依赖项位于
calm what is it it's a sin grid Java
冷静一下这是一个罪恶的网格Java
right yes I think so and 4.2 1.1 yeah
是的，我想是这样，4.2 1.1是
wada okay so that's there now in our
和田好吧，那现在在我们那里
main our code we're going to create a
主要是我们的代码，我们将创建一个
simple function that sends to our to
发送给我们的简单功能
some it will just send it to ourselves
有些会把它发送给我们自己
basically we're gonna send a an email to
基本上，我们要发送电子邮件至
ourselves in order to do that we need to
为了做到这一点，我们需要
send grid client so when we say at being
发送网格客户端，所以当我们说在
send grid API that's the interface we
发送网格API，这是我们的接口
might as well send grid and we can just
不如发送网格，我们可以
call this send grid and in order for
称为此发送网格，并为了
this to work well need this environment
要正常工作需要这种环境
rebel I happen to have this environment
反叛我碰巧有这种环境
variable on my local machine so any
我的本地机器上的变量，所以任何
tests I run will work but this isn't
我运行的测试可以工作，但这不是
going to work without that environment
没有那种环境就可以工作
variable in the in the cluster in the
变量在集群中
created cluster so we need to actually
创建了集群，所以我们需要实际
set that up and we'll talk about secrets
设置好，我们将讨论秘密
management here in kubernetes in just a
kubernetes中的管理
second so I'm going to say return new
第二，所以我要说返回新的
SendGrid whoops I need the actual
我需要实际的SendGrid哦
implementation the concrete one passing
实施具体一过
in the key alrighty good got that and
在关键好事中得到了
we'll create a function that takes in a
我们将创建一个函数
string which is the email and it'll
字符串，这是电子邮件，它将
return a boolean sent right
返回正确发送的布尔值
so imagine you have something that you
所以想像你有东西
know somebody signs up for an account or
知道有人注册了帐户或
something like that and you want to do a
这样的事情，你想做一个
confirmation email or whatever this is
确认电子邮件或其他任何内容
one of those things where it might take
其中可能需要的事情之一
a little longer than you are prepared to
比您准备的时间长一点
wait you might want to format stuff you
等一下，你可能想格式化你的东西
might need to prepare images whatever
可能需要准备图像
you this could be the kind of stuff that
你这可能是那种东西
you run as a cron job it might be a
您作为cron工作运行，可能是
report that runs or whatever and this is
运行的报告或其他内容，这是
the this is a perfect example of the
这是一个完美的例子
kind of work that I would be very happy
我会很高兴的那种工作
to throw into am into a function as a
投入到函数中
service platform we used to talk about
我们以前谈论的服务平台
tuple spaces you know the idea of a
元组空间，你知道一个
cluster of workers that could then just
一群工人然后可以
aggressively consume you know these are
积极消耗你知道这些是
the greedy consumers they would
他们会贪婪的消费者
aggressively works till they take work
积极工作直到他们上班
off of a queue and process their work
不用排队处理他们的工作
and then and then disappear right um and
然后再消失吧
this is the kind of stuff that we want
这是我们想要的东西
to wait we know we can send support very
等待，我们知道我们可以发送支持
naturally using a function as it serves
自然使用功能
run time so here we are a new function
运行时间，所以这里是一个新功能
and in our function we're going to take
在我们的职能中，我们将采取
the email and I'm going to confirm that
电子邮件，我将确认
it was sent and in order to send we need
它已发送，为了发送，我们需要
to use the we need to use the send good
使用我们需要使用发送好的
client okay
客户还可以
so let's see I don't know if we even
所以让我们看看我不知道我们是否
need that
需要那个
probably not email hello all right
可能没有通过电子邮件打招呼好吗
now let's see if I can remember this API
现在让我们看看我是否还记得这个API
email is from new email spring - tips at
电子邮件来自新的电子邮件春季-的提示
Josh long calm alright that's not a real
约什（Josh）冷静了好久
email address would that it would be I
电子邮件地址会是我
should actually probably create it
实际上应该创建它
subject it will be beautiful riff
主题将是美丽的即兴
alright email - will be - will be the
好的电子邮件-将-将是
email that we get as a as a parameter
作为参数收到的电子邮件
wouldn't it so there we go the content
是不是所以我们去了内容
the content let's see about this equals
内容让我们看看这等于
I think it's just text plain if memory
我认为这只是文字上的记忆
serves and it'll be hello beautiful
服务，它将变得美丽
function as a service or you know what
充当服务或您知道什么
just go for the traditional hello world
去传统的你好世界
since that's super appropriate mail is
因为那是超级合适的邮件
the helper object that it comes from the
来自于的帮助对象
SendGrid api - because what we're doing
SendGrid API-因为我们在做什么
is we're using the same great api to
是我们使用相同的出色API
post to their rest api so really we've
发布到他们的休息api，所以我们真的
just got some fancy composite types that
刚刚得到了一些花哨的复合类型
we can use to make short work of
我们可以用来缩短
marshaling back and forth to their api
来回封送他们的api
so - and then content everyone up okay
所以-然后让每个人都满意
and now we come comes to the action it
现在我们来行动吧
now comes the actual interactions with
现在出现了与
their same good client so what we're
他们相同的好客户，所以我们
saying is request
说的是要求
well are equals new requests and passing
等于等于新的要求和传递
in
在
they say our dot set method method
他们说我们的点集方法
equals post our dot set body
等于发布我们的点集身体
that'll be mail dot build all right put
这将是邮件点构建没事了
that back here throw new one-time
回到这里一次新的
exception bubble that up to the client
由客户决定的异常泡沫
what else do I know what our dot n point
我还知道我们的n点是什么
mail send and I think that's it I think
邮件发送，我认为就是这样
that's the critical lines that we need
这就是我们需要的关键线
right now we need to actually do it so
现在我们需要实际这样做
let's get the response will say send
让我们得到回应会说发送
great API dot that was an API yep R
很棒的API点，是API y R
then I'll give us back a response and
然后我会给我们回复
then using the response we want to
然后使用我们想要的响应
confirm that it was sent response dot
确认已发送响应点
get status code should equal HTTP status
获取状态码应等于HTTP状态
dot okay that value returned sent okay
点好，返回值已发送好
there we are so there's our simple
我们在那里，所以我们很简单
function and that should do it that's a
功能，应该做到这一点
very simple example obviously you would
很简单的例子显然你会
have HTML and formatting and I'm sure
有HTML和格式，我敢肯定
you'd have a designer and there
你会有设计师，在那里
somewhere and all sorts of stuff okay
某个地方，各种各样的东西都可以
we have just a very simple example now
我们现在有一个非常简单的例子
this is a function it's gonna be called
这是一个函数，它将被称为
mail and in order for it to do its work
邮件并为其执行工作
as you can as you know we need this
尽你所能，我们需要这个
environment variable this key here
环境变量此键在这里
normally in fact I could go a step
通常我实际上可以走一步
further I could say you know SendGrid
更进一步，我可以说你知道SendGrid
dot API key and then let's bring that
点API密钥，然后让我们带上它
same good API key this will actually
同样好的API密钥，实际上
auto configure a same grid object for me
自动为我配置相同的网格对象
this is a spring boot auto-configuration
这是一个Spring Boot自动配置
so I could say spring that's Ingrid an
所以我可以说春天是英格丽
API key equals this here right
API密钥等于此处
so there we are that would be the
所以我们在那里
environment and this will give me a
环境，这会给我一个
SendGrid object so I'm good so yeah so
SendGrid对象，所以我很好，是的，所以
it'll it'll create the http/2 kid this
它会创建http / 2这个孩子
SendGrid
SendGrid
api key just like i did so we could use
像我一样的api键，所以我们可以使用
that that's actually probably even
那实际上可能甚至
cleaner so let's do that
清洁工，让我们这样做
actually well just the spring but-- do
实际上只是春天，但是-
they work here for us all right now
他们现在在这里为我们工作
we've got the application we've got the
我们有应用程序，我们有
SendGrid
SendGrid
implementation I think that's that we
实施我认为那就是我们
need to that we need to now deploy this
需要我们现在需要部署它
application and in order for us to do
申请并为了我们做
that we need to tell kubernetes about
我们需要告诉kubernetes
that API key so this is where it gets a
该API密钥，因此这是获取密钥的地方
little tedious we need to actually dive
我们需要潜水的乏味
into kubernetes secrets let's see so
进入kubernetes的秘密，让我们拭目以待
here I have this value running on my
在这里我有这个价值
local machine I'll say echo SendGrid API
我会说本地计算机echo SendGrid API
key and I want to write this out to in
关键，我想写出来
an API key txt file
API密钥txt文件
I've got the environment vailable I'm a
我的环境适用于我
local machine I want that to be on the
我希望它在本地计算机上
local file system you'll forgive me if I
本地文件系统，如果我会原谅我
don't cat that environment rebel there
不要在那儿反抗环境
I'm gonna say Kubb CTL create secret
我要说的是Kubb CTL创建秘密
generic SendGrid API key and I'm gonna
通用的SendGrid API密钥，我要
say I wanted to come from a file and I'm
说我想来自文件，而我
notice that there's a bit of a there's
请注意，那里有一些
two things happening here I'm saying
我说的是这里发生的两件事
create a secret called SendGrid api key
创建一个名为SendGrid api密钥的秘密
and then thats in grid secret can have a
然后多数民众赞成在网格秘密可以有一个
dictionary of values of keys and values
键和值的值字典
believe it or not so the key it's not
信不信由你，关键不是
just a key and then on the value it's
只是一个关键，然后在价值上
actually a key that then gives you
实际上是一把钥匙，然后会给你
access to a dictionary and so I here I'm
访问字典，所以我在这里
saying again SendGrid api key now this
现在再说一次SendGrid api键
is you know if you're doing it using a
您是否知道您是否正在使用
password you'd have sanguin api key from
您具有来自的sanguin api密钥的密码
file equals user name equals and then
文件等于用户名等于，然后
the value from the file and then - -
文件中的值，然后--
from file password equals and then the
来自文件的密码等于，然后
equals password then equals the file
等于密码然后等于文件
from the password file right so I'm
从密码文件中，所以我
going to say it's Ingrid API key equals
会说这是Ingrid API密钥等于
dot
点
API key dot txt
API密钥点txt
all right so coop cuddle great secret
好吧，所以，cood拥抱伟大的秘密
generic sanguine API key from file
文件中的通用sanguine API密钥
SendGrid - API key dot API key dot txt
SendGrid-API关键点API关键点txt
all right now if I look at that I say
现在，如果我看着我说
coop cuddle get secrets all right and I
小屋拥抱获得所有的秘密吧，我
can say coop cuddle get secret SendGrid
可以说小屋拥抱得到秘密的SendGrid
API key
API密钥
oh yeah mo so I'm actually I don't need
哦，是的，所以我实际上我不需要
to do this but this is kind of
为此，但这是一种
interesting you can see that this is the
有趣的是，您可以看到这是
this invocation this that there's - oh
这个调用是这样的-哦
yeah mo tells kubernetes to write the
yeah mo告诉kubernetes写
definition of that resource out into a
将该资源定义为
config file into the jason the amell's
配置文件进入杰森·阿梅尔的
stands us that I would need to - then if
让我们站起来，我需要-然后，如果
I want to version control that's like
我想对版本进行控制
actually version control like this and
实际上是这样的版本控制和
then use the cuckoo cuddle you know
然后用你知道的布谷鸟抱抱
crate secret and then tell just use this
板条箱秘密，然后告诉就用这个
file instead of me doing it man and the
文件而不是我做的人和
command line so there's that and that
命令行，就是那样
what I want to do what I want to do is I
我想做的是我想做的
need to create that function I need to
需要创建该功能，我需要
actually - I need to create that
实际上-我需要创建一个
function first and I'm gonna have to
首先运行，我将不得不
create it and then run it basic I want I
创建它，然后运行它基本我想要我
want I I could do this a number ways but
想要II可以通过多种方式做到这一点，但是
just to be consistent I'm just gonna say
为了保持一致，我只想说
create the function - i mailer
创建功能-我的邮件
- n is Manor that's the name - a is I
-n是庄园，就是名字-a是我
mean do a maven clean package first i
意思是先做一个行家清洁包
just relized
刚刚关系
mailer may even clean package i'm gonna
邮递员甚至可能会清洁包裹
create the function first and it's gonna
首先创建功能，然后
fail but I don't care and then I'm going
失败但我不在乎然后我要去
to update the config file for the
更新配置文件
resources for the function resource that
功能资源的资源
we are given when we create the function
我们在创建函数时得到
so I'll say riff create Java
所以我会说riff创建Java
- I mater and mailer a target Manor
-我向目标庄园寄送邮件
handler will be male and main will be
经理将是男性，主要将是
equal to calm example dot mater
等于冷静的例子
but is it major application yeah that is
但这是主要应用吗
let's just copy that reference just to
让我们将引用复制到
be darn sure okay so that's the UM the
该死的好吧，那是UM
rift create Java IMS I am okay
我还好
create that and you can see I've got
创建它，你可以看到我有
these new resources now and as before
这些新资源现在和以前一样
I'm going to open up these this function
我将打开这些功能
config here and this time I'm going to
在这里配置，这次我要
change it to reflect our new secret so I
更改它以反映我们的新秘密，所以我
want to go to container and we'll say e
想去集装箱，我们会说e
and V and we'll say - name will be send
和V，我们会说-名称将被发送
grid API key the value from and here
网格API密钥的值
we're going to use the secret key
我们将使用密钥
reference so a secret key ref name and
引用，所以一个秘密密钥引用名称和
this is where the dictionary comes in so
这是字典的来源
they like key in that little dictionary
他们喜欢那本小字典里的钥匙
if you will is some good API key the the
如果您会使用一些好的API密钥，
key that we want it's in grid API key
我们希望它位于网格API密钥中的密钥
all right
好吧
and then that's it that's everything we
这就是我们要做的一切
need and with that in place that should
需要并在适当的地方
create an environment variable in our
在我们的环境中创建一个环境变量
container in the function container and
功能容器中的容器和
make loops and make that available to
制作循环并将其提供给
the java application which will then
Java应用程序
boot up with this in place so now I'm
启动到位，所以现在我
gonna say riff update right all right so
会说riff更新没事，所以
good so there we go there's our
好，所以我们去那里是我们的
application let's now try it out okay so
应用程序，现在让我们尝试一下吧
I've got this this is my inbox here for
我有这个，这是我的收件箱
Joshua Josh song calm I'm looking for
Joshua Josh我在寻找歌曲平静
bootiful riff as the subject here right
i谐即兴即兴主题在这里
that's what this is right here so let's
这就是这里，所以让我们
go ahead and now create some traffic
继续，现在创造一些流量
I'll create some requests where's our
我将创建一些请求，这是我们的
here we are okay I'm going to say riff
这里我们可以，我要说即兴
publish - I made er - D is Josh
发布-我犯了错误-D是Josh
that Josh long com- are so we're going
乔什·朗·科姆（Josh Long com）-所以我们要去
to send a request to Manor publish it
发送请求给庄园发布
there and it should if we've deployed
在那里，如果我们已经部署
everything quickly result in eight email
一切很快就会产生八封电子邮件
arriving my inbox in just a second or so
只需一秒钟左右即可到达我的收件箱
creating the container up and running
创建并运行容器
it failed what did I do wrong so kale -
失败了，我做错了什么，所以羽衣甘蓝-
D mailer kales a nice command-line
D mailer kales一个不错的命令行
utility to do debug this kind of stuff
实用程序来调试这种东西
did it work
它工作了吗
looks like it worked
看起来很有效
well what happened there
好那里发生了什么
clearly it got the message
显然它得到了信息
did I do something wrong with the code
我在代码中做错了吗
a very curious
一个很好奇的
so it ran and I got a false that's the
所以它跑了，我得到了一个错误，那就是
factory get log dot info II died when I
工厂获取日志点信息II当我死时
don't eat at Prince Dec trace although
虽然不要在十二月王子踪影中吃饭
it seemed that that should be there
似乎应该在那里
anyway so you know what I'm gonna go
无论如何，所以你知道我要去哪里
ahead and try and control how this thing
继续尝试并控制这件事
gets created that was working SendGrid
创建正在工作的SendGrid
API key bean SendGrid API SendGrid API
API密钥bean SendGrid API SendGrid API
that value a string key turn new
该值将字符串键转换为新
SendGrid API key alright looks like it
SendGrid API密钥看起来不错
should be the same though
应该是一样的
so we'll say email from subject email -
所以我们说主题电子邮件中的电子邮件-
you know - is here you know from content
你知道-在这里你从内容中知道
is text plain hello world is it not from
是纯文本的hello世界，不是来自
subject to content yeah request method
视内容而定是请求方法
mail send mail that build good API that
邮件发送建立良好API的邮件
request
请求
okay
好的
hello
你好
functional world hi - I wonder if it's
功能世界您好-我想知道是否
some sort of spam filter hi to the
某种垃圾邮件过滤器
functional world
功能世界
alright hello and optionally I'm Kent
好的，你好，我是肯特
maven clean package and RIF update eval
Maven的清洁包和RIF更新评估
docker I start me cube docker env
我启动我多维数据集docker env
alright
好的
oh wait I did give those if sent false
哦，等等，如果发送错误，我确实给了那些
8:19 and there's another 822 OS I did
8:19还有另外一个822 OS
get them why is it returned false oh
让他们为什么会返回假哦
it's interesting I got some other code
有趣的是我得到了一些其他代码
but nonetheless the emails did arrive I
但是尽管如此，电子邮件确实到达了我
just didn't refresh the email counselor
只是没有刷新电子邮件顾问
so that's silly I'm some sort of issue
所以这很愚蠢，我有点问题
there with the um if status code what is
还有um如果状态码是什么
the issue with the status code response
状态码响应的问题
type get status code equals HTP okay
类型获取状态代码等于HTP可以
that value it's false and yet it's
该值是错误的，但它是
working there so hello to the function
在那里工作，所以功能很好
one all right so that does work so you
一个好吧，这样就行了，所以你
can see my point there's opportunities
可以看到我的观点有机会
there you should definitely understand
那里你一定要明白
good before you run this example so
在运行此示例之前很好，因此
clearly I need to do better there but
显然我需要在那里做得更好，但是
that does work the result is that we can
确实有效的结果是我们可以
send emails with the invocation of a
发送带有以下内容的电子邮件
single request now taking a moment here
现在只需要一点时间
just to focus on what's happening you
只是专注于正在发生的事情
can see that I'm sending a riff
可以看到我正在发送即兴演奏
published and that's actually posting to
已发布，实际上正在发布到
the the HTTP gateway inside of it's it's
它里面的HTTP网关是
the you know there's actually a
你知道实际上有一个
incantation that you can use to get the
你可以用来获得的咒语
the HTTP gateway for project riff and
HTTP网关用于项目riff和
that incantation I think they're even
那个咒语，我想他们甚至
kind enough to put it here on the blog
足够好，可以放在博客上
when you I think when you do this helm
当我想起当你掌舵时
chart it'll actually show you the
图表实际上会向您显示
environment variables you need to be
您需要的环境变量
able to arrive at that same URL so you
能够到达相同的URL，所以您
know the secret to get those URLs and
知道获取这些URL的秘密，并且
I'm sure you'd have that figured out at
我相信你会在
some point so you can actually just post
有一点，所以你实际上可以发布
you don't actually you don't have to use
您实际上不需要使用
republish you can just make an inch to
重新发布就可以
be post to HTTP you know your gateway IP
发布到HTTP，您知道您的网关IP
and port for such requests for session
以及此类会话请求的端口
then the name of the function and you'll
然后函数的名称，您将
get the response back all right my
得到正确的回复我的
friends with that we've looked at ever
我们曾经看过的朋友
so briefly at a number of different
所以简要地讲一些不同的
aspects of functions as a service with
作为服务的功能方面
them with project RIF the new open
他们与项目RIF新开放
source Apache License function as a
源Apache许可证功能
service runtime from pivotal and spring
关键和春天的服务运行时
cloud function the easiest way to build
云功能构建的最简单方法
functions that work in a number of
可以在多个
different functions and service
不同的功能和服务
platforms regardless of
平台，无论
they're the the destination using spring
他们是春季的目的地
and taking advantage of all the sort of
并利用各种
things that you might expect to be able
您可能期望能够做的事情
to use from a spring good application
从春季良好的应用程序中使用
including properties and so on and we
包括属性等等，我们
also looked at kubernetes secrets as a
也将kubernetes的秘密视为
way of you know how do you tell your
你的方式知道你如何告诉你的
application about these about these
关于这些的应用关于这些
different properties right that you need
您需要的不同属性
so you can do that using Combinator
所以你可以使用组合器做到这一点
secrets config Maps or just or you could
秘密配置地图或只是或您可以
actually just hard code them in the
实际上只是将它们硬编码在
function resource there right don't put
正确的功能资源不要放
the passwords there don't definitely
那里的密码不一定
don't put that there but configuration
不要放在那儿，但要配置
values themselves that need to be that
重视自己需要
need to change in production versus for
需要改变生产与
example development you can have the
您可以拥有的示例开发
defaults in your develop environment and
在您的开发环境中默认
put the non secret non you know secure
把你知道的非秘密非安全
stuff just directly in the function
只是直接在函数中
resource all right my friends I hope you
好的，我的朋友们，我希望你
got something out of this and as usual
像往常一样从中得到一些东西
thanks for watching and we'll see you
谢谢收看，我们见
next time
下次
you
您